Margaret Bourke-White Papers
Margaret Bourke-White Papers
- Recordings
  - Phonodiscs
    - Margaret Bourke White Talk; March of Time, 2/3/44; mbw_204; 1 disc
    - Mary Margaret McBride; WEAF; Parts 1 through 7, 4/22/43; mbw_226, mbw_227, mbw_228, mbw_229; 3 discs
      First disc is restricted due to condition.
    - MBW 964, mbw_255; "M.B.W. Part 1 M.B.W. Part 3 964 I (Side A) 964 II (Side B)"; 1 disc
    - MBW 969 Part 5, mbw_256; 1 disc
    - [MBW] 990, mbw_260; Notes from reference tape #1422: "Attempt to photograph studio (cont.), impressions of him, discussion of portrait of Stalin's mother, daytime air-raid, impressions of the front, Banquet before her departure"; 1 disc
    - [MBW] 991, mbw_261; Notes from reference tape #1422: "Describes visit to USSR to see effect of non-aggression pact, just as war broke out, impressions of war, women training for factories, impressions of Moscow, air-raid, attempts to photograph Stalin."; 1 disc
    - North African Air Forces, 1943; mbw_247 through mbw_250; original sleeve label: #37a North Africa Air Force 5-14-43 KMTR, Hollywood"; 4 discs
    - Of Interest to Women, mbw_253; 1 side; 1 disc
    - Painting with Light by Margaret Bourke-White; John Citizen Sees the Light, mbw_257, mbw_258; 2 discs
    - Profile - Miss Margaret B. White; Out 33 1/3, 1955; mbw_254; original label: "Recorded at Charlotte, NC; Before my speech; June 1955; 1 side Partial"; 1 disc
    - Readers & Writers Margaret Bourke-White, WQXR, Parts 1-3, 6/2/42; mbw_238, mbw_239; 2 discs
    - Tex & Jinx; Broadcast on WNBC, DUBB, Sides 2, 3, 5, 6, 8, 9, 11, 12, 5-30-53; mbw_217 through mbw_220; 4 discs
    - Tex & Jinx, WNBC, DUBB, Sides 1, 2, 5, 6, 7, 8, 11, 12, 5-4-53; mbw_212, mbw_213, mbw_215, mbw_216; 4 discs
    - Tex & Jinx End of the Record Low Level (Studio); WNBC; DUBB; Sides 3 and 9, 5-4-53; mbw_214; 1 disc
    - This Is The Picture 11:30 to 12 mid CBS parts 1-9, 11/15/45; mbw_221 through mbw_225; 5 discs
    - Travels in Russia, part 2, mbw_244; 1 disc
      Disc is restricted due to condition.
    - War Department Special Service Department presents We Who Fight Series: NY10 Program No. 16; Sides A and B, mbw_259; Miss Agnes Smedley, Yeoman 1/C Lacey Pomplon Miss Margaret Bourke-White Golden Gate Quartet, LT. Frederick Carlton Edwin C. Hill, MC; 1 disc
    - We The People, Feb. 14, 1943; mbw_205; 1 disc
    - We The People; Margaret Bourke-White Spot; Parts 1 and 2, 10/21/45; mbw_201; 1 disc
    - We the People, interview with MBW on Gandhi, 10 February 1948; mbw_188; 1 disc
    - We The People - M.B.W Parts 1 and 2 CBS, undated; mbw_195; 1 disc
    - Wide Horizons, Parts 1-6; WOR, 4/16/44; mbw_197, mbw_199, mbw_200; 3 discs
    - Wide Horizons; Margaret Bourke-White (Sketch & Interview); Parts 1 and 2; WOR, 4/16/44; mbw_198; 1 disc
    - Unidentified, mbw_246; 1 disc
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "And So My Ship Came In", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - "Assignments for Publication," The Complete Photographer, Sept. 20, 1941 (Box 57)
    - "Assignments for Publication," The Encyclopedia of Photography, 1965 (Box 57)
    - "The Best Advise I Ever Had," Reader's Digest [British Edition], 1957 (Box 57)
    - "Bird in Flight," The Washington Post, Jan. 11, 1942 (Box 57)
    - "Caldwell Calls Red Soldier Unlike Any Other in History," PM, Oct. 22, 1941 (Box 57)
    - "Camel Corps--Syria," U.S. Camera The Year's Photography Vol. II, 1941 (Box 57)
    - "A Career in Photography", manuscript drafts (Box 57)
    - "Challenge to Women," The Hartford Times guest editorial, Nov. 29, 1951 (Box 57)
    - "Dust Changes America," The Nation, May 22, 1935 (Box 57)
    - "F.D.R. and the Three Blonds", manuscript for Introduction (Box 57)
    - "Famous Lady's Indomitable Fight," Life, June 22, 1959 (Box 57)
    - "Favorite Pictures," American Society of Magazine Photographers' Picture Annual, 1957 (Box 57)
    - "I'll Monitor Your Breath", manuscript drafts (Box 57)
      See also Portrait of Myself early drafts-deletions.
    - "Introduction for Lens Portfolio", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - "The Jesuits in America," Life, Oct. 11, 1954 (Box 57)
    - "Margaret Bourke-White in the Lyons Den," New York Post, Aug. 21, 1943 (Box 57)
    - "The Nizam Capitulates," The Star Weekly, May 7, 1949 (Box 57)
    - "Photographing This World," The Nation, Feb. 19, 1936 (Box 57)
    - "Pictures of Czecho-slovakia," Direction, Jan./Feb. 1939 (Box 57)
    - "Resourcefulness," Think, Feb. 1948 (Box 57)
    - "Shooting from a Whirlibird", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - [Six Part Series on Russia], The New York Times, 1932; manuscript drafts; 2 folders (Box 57)
    - "Spin, Please, Madam Photographer", manuscript drafts (Box 57)
    - "They Called Me Incurable," Reader's Digest, Oct. 1959 (Box 57)
    - "Women in Lifeboats," Life, Feb. 22, 1943 (Box 57)
    - "Women in Photography," Famous Photographers School, 1964; manuscript (Box 57)
    - "Words About Pictures, " Infinity, June 1958 (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "Eight miles straight up ...", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "General Notes for Journal-American Article", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "In the little known war ..." (Korea), manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "The life of a photographer ...", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "Normally, one bandage ..." (National War Fund), manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "Photography is a window ...", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "When Portrait of Myself came out ...", 1963; manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "Several summers ago ...", manuscript draft (Box 57)
    - Untitled, "When I remember how I ..." (Van Gogh exhibit), manuscript draft (Box 57)
  - Books
    - Dear Fatherland, Rest Quietly [DEA], Chapters 1-18, manuscript drafts; 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Dear Fatherland, Rest Quietly [DEA], captions for photo sequences, manuscript (Box 58)
    - Dear Fatherland, Rest Quietly [DEA], book cover, production records (Box 58)
    - Eyes on Russia, production records (Box 58)
    - Halfway to Freedom, book notes; 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Halfway to Freedom, Introduction-Chapter VII; 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Halfway to Freedom, Chapters VIII-XXVI - manuscript drafts; 4 folders (Box 59)
    - Halfway to Freedom, cover, ads, production records (Box 59)
    - North of the Danube, book notes (Box 59)
    - Portrait of Myself, book notes; 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Portrait of Myself, book notes; 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Portrait of Myself, calendars of travels (Box 60)
    - Portrait of Myself, chapter sequences, lists of pictures (Box 60)
    - Portrait of Myself, deletions, manuscript drafts; 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Portrait of Myself, Table of Contents, Chapters 1-11 manuscript drafts; 8 folders (Box 61)
    - Portrait of Myself, Chapters 12-20 manuscript drafts; 8 folders (Box 62)
    - Portrait of Myself, Chapters 21-28 manuscript drafts; 7 folders (Box 63)
    - Portrait of Myself, Chapters 29-31, postscript manuscript drafts; 3 folders (Box 64)
    - A Report on the American Jesuits, book notes (Box 64)
    - A Report on the American Jesuits, "Note by Margaret Bourke-White" - manuscript draft and photo layout (Box 64)
    - Shooting the Russian War, book notes (Box 64)
    - Shooting the Russian War, Introduction-Chapter VI manuscript drafts; 3 folders (Box 64)
    - Shooting the Russian War, Chapter VII-XVIII, glossary, appendix manuscript drafts; 5 folders (Box 65)
    - They Called It "Purple Heart Valley", book notes (Box 65)
    - They Called It "Purple Heart Valley", Chapters I-III - manuscript drafts (Box 65)
    - They Called It "Purple Heart Valley", Chapters IV-XIX, "Note About the Author" manuscript drafts; 5 folders (Box 66)
    - They Called It "Purple Heart Valley", official censored chapters - manuscript (Box 66)
    - They Called It "Purple Heart Valley", miscellany (Box 66)
    - You Have Seen Their Faces, "Notes On Photographs by Margaret Bourke-White" manuscript drafts (Box 66)
  - Interviews
    - Adventurous Careers for Women," WNEW Radio, May 8, 1935 (Box 67)
    - "Margaret Bourke-White/Erskine Caldwell," Counterpoint / Roy Newquist (Box 67)
    - The Proceedings of "Youth Wants to Know", July 8, 1956; radio transcript, printed material (Box 67)
    - "Success Stories" (Box 67)
    - WABC Radio, Gold Medal Flour Program, Aug. 31, 1936 (Box 67)
    - WLTH Radio, Feb. 16, 1933 (Box 67)
    - WMCA Radio, June 20, 1935 (Box 67)
    - WPCH Radio, 1933; notes, outline (Box 67)
    - Unknown, June 30, 1970 (Box 67)
    - Unknown radio (Box 67)
  - Lectures
    - "Advice to Embryonic Photographers", July 1937; notes (Box 67)
    - "Behind the Lenses" (Korea), Jan. 13, 1953 (Box 67)
    - "Creative Staff Meeting", Feb. 1, 1933 (Box 67)
    - Czechoslovakia, Sept. 30, 1938 (Box 67)
    - Keynote Speech, econd Annual Photojournalism Conference (Box 67)
    - Korea speech, 1952; "Transcript of speech by MBW on Korea, Sacramento Cal for use in speech practice", possibly a transcript of one of the recordings in the collection (Box 67)
    - "Lenses Behind the News" (Box 67)
    - N.B.C., Jan. 1932 (Box 67)
    - "Opportunities for Young Women in the Field of Photography," RCA Women's Radio Review, June 14, 1934 (Box 67)
    - "Photography Changes Perception," New School for Social Research, Mar. 13, 1934 (Box 67)
    - "Radio Talk Delivered Over the Chinese International Broadcasting Station at Chungking", 1941 (Box 67)
    - Russia, Dec. 15, 1932 (Box 67)
    - Sacramento lecture, 1952; "Transcript of Sacramento lecture Disc #5 - by MBW", possibly a transcript of one of the recordings in the collection (Box 67)
    - "What Must We Do to Improve the Health and Well-Being of the American People?" town meeting, Dec. 8, 1941 (Box 67)
    - "Wisconsin Speech" (Box 67)
    - "Women of Achievement" (Box 67)
    - "World of Art," NBC broadcast, Feb. 1954 (Box 67)
    - WOR Radio, 1931 (Box 67)
    - WRNY Radio, Jan. 26, 1952 (Box 67)
  - Notes
    - Datebooks, 1950; 1954 (Box 67)
    - Datebooks, 1960 (Box 68)
    - Dust storm assignment, 1935 (Box 68)
    - Exhibitions (Box 68)
    - India (Box 68)
    - Items on loan, 1957-1958 (Box 68)
    - Japan (Box 68)
    - Japan notebooks (Box 68)
    - Jesuits (Box 68)
    - Korea, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Korea notebooks, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Life assignments, various) (Box 69)
    - Life assignments, various, captions (Box 69)
    - Life assignments, dams (Box 69)
    - Lists and addresses (Box 69)
    - Movies (Box 69)
    - Natural history, 1933-1935 (Box 69)
    - Parkinson's Disease, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Photography - technical data (Box 69)
    - Photomurals (Box 70)
    - Selassie, Haile, See Notes: South Africa.
    - South Africa, 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Soviet Union (Box 70)
    - Studio information (Box 70)
    - TV appearances (Box 70)
    - United States (Box 70)
    - World War II, England (Box 70)
    - World War II, Germany (Box 70)
    - World War II, Italy (Box 71)
    - World War II, North Africa, Dec. 1942-Jan. 1943 (Box 71)
    - World War II, miscellaneous (Box 71)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 71)
  - Miscellany
    - Book (unpublished), typescript; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Book chapter on Gandhi, "Heroes for Our Time", 1968 (Box 72)
    - Juvenilia
      - "An Ill-treated Individual", Feb. 28, 1921; manuscript (Box 72)
      - "The Biography of a Baby Robin", undated; manuscript (Box 72)
      - "Continuation School", undated; typescript (Box 72)
      - "In a King's Dwelling Am I", undated; typescript (Box 72)
      - "A Modern Pilgrimage", Apr. 18, 1921; manuscript (Box 72)
      - "Teddy", 1919; The Oracle, p. 10-12; typescript (Box 72)
    - Motion picture material, outlines, captions, narrative, reel sequences (typescript), notes (handwritten) for Eyes on Russia; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Clippings (Box 72)
    - Poetry, mix of handwritten and typescript (Box 72)
    - Reviews
      - Book: Country of Youth, in The Nation, 1935; galley proof (Box 72)
      - Book: Portrait of a Year, in The Nation, 1935; typescript (Box 72)
      - Motion picture: Hell on Earth, undated; typescript (Box 72)